The younger brother, Ashura,
has been reincarnated in you.
(ハゴロモ)弟アシュラは
お前に転生したのだ。
(ハゴロモ)わしの目には はっきりと
アシュラのチャクラが→
My eyes can clearly see
Ashura's chakra clinging about you.
お前に寄り添うのが見える。
《ナルト : もしかして…》
I wonder if...
あまり驚かないところを見ると→
You don't seem too surprised.
お前 実は アシュラの存在を
自分の中に感じたことが→
Perhaps, you have sensed
Ashura's presence
あるんじゃないのか？
inside you already?
やはり そうか。
I thought as much.
Then you must know already...
それなら
もう わかっているはずだな。
兄インドラの転生者が 誰なのかも。
who is the reincarnate
of the older one, Indra...
サスケ…。
Sasuke...
((シカマル : サスケが そんなことを…。
Sasuke did that?
(シノ)ああ 信じられない事態だな。
Yes, it's an unbelievable situation.
(赤丸)クゥーン。
だから サスケのことは
俺に任せてほしいんだ。
That's why I want you
to let me handle Sasuke.
(テンテン)サスケを一人で やる!?
You want to take on
Sasuke alone?
そんなんで 私たちみんなが
納得できるわけないでしょ！
How can you expect us
to agree to that?
テンテンの言うとおりだ ナルト。
Tenten is right, Naruto.
お前一人のわがままには
つきあっていられない。
We can't just give in
to your stubbornness.
なぜなら これは
里の大きな問題だ。
The reason is...
this is a big problem
for the village.
これは わがままじゃねえんだ。
I'm not being stubborn.
(キバ)帰ってから
詳しく話すっつうからよ…。
You said you'd give us
the details when we got home,
何を言うかと思えば！
俺たちだって 覚悟して→
but I never thought
this is what you'd say!
We've all made up our minds
to kill Sasuke!
サスケのことを殺すって
決めたんだぞ！
(シカマル)おい ナルト お前 まさか
一人でやるって言っときながら→
Hey, Naruto, I hope you're not saying
you'll get Sasuke all by yourself,
サスケをかばう
ってんじゃねえだろうな。
when you're actually planning
to protect him.
ああ サスケをかばうなんて
そんなつもりは ねえよ。
No, I have no intention
of protecting Sasuke.
(ネジ)五影会談で
大立ち回りをやらかし→
After all the fighting
at the Five Kage Summit,
その後 ダンゾウと戦って
そこまで弱っていたサスケなら→
and fighting Danzo...
If Sasuke was so weakened
at that time,
なんで 一気に片をつけなかった？
why didn't you take him out
right then?
(サクラ)マダラも いたし！
Madara was there too!
そんなに簡単な感じじゃなかった。
それに…。
It didn't seem like it would
be an easy task. Besides...
だからってよ みすみす
逃がすことはねえだろ！
That's no reason to let him
get away so easily!
おい ナルト オメエは強ぇんだぜ。
Hey, Naruto...
You're strong.
ペイン ぶっ倒した
英雄ってヤツだろうが！
You're the hero who took
down Pain, aren't you?!
英雄？
ああ。
Hero?
サスケの野郎も
あん時みてぇによ！
Yeah. You could take Sasuke down
like you did back then.
そうじゃねえんだ。
あん？
That's not true.
(そんなんで 今のサスケは倒せねえ。
それが わかった))
I wouldn't be able to beat Sasuke
with something like that now.
That's what I found out.
《アイツの中にも…》
Inside him too, is...
そうなんだろ？
Isn't that right?
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
nigirishime ta yume ga koboreochi sou na
When the dream I've attained is
toki ni kagitte omoidasu no
about to fall apart, I remember
aitsu no ano yasashii kao
His kind expression,
mune no oku ga mata tsuyoku nareru no
the core of my heart is strengthened once again
bukkirabou no kokoro ni fire
My blunt mind is set ablaze,
gutto kuru ashita o tsukami tain da
I want to grasp tomorrow as it comes at me
mada mi nu sekai wa kowaku nai
I'm not afraid of the world I haven't seen,
shinji ta mirai desho hora let’s try!
isn't this the future we believed in? Come on Let's try!
kazoekire nai ano namida wa sou sa niji ni kawaru darou
Those countless tears, will they change into a rainbow?
osaekire nai kanashimi mo
That sorrow I can't contain
itsuka wa dakishime rareru ka na
Will I be able to embrace you someday?
yawa na haato ga uzukidashi tara
When my feeble heart begins to throb
arittake asu ni kisu shite ageyou
I give all of my kisses to tomorrow
furue ta mama no chiisana kobushi o tsuyoku mata nigitte
Still trembling, I clench my tiny fist tightly
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
The Sage of Six Paths
(ハゴロモ)兄 インドラは
お前に転生したのだ。
The older brother, Indra,
has been reincarnated in you.
わしの目には はっきりと
インドラのチャクラが→
My eyes can clearly see
Indra's chakra clinging about you.
お前に寄り添うのが見える。
あまり驚かないところを見ると→
You don't seem too surprised.
お前 実は インドラの存在を→
Perhaps, you have sensed
Indra's presence inside you already?
自分の中に感じたことが
あるんじゃないのか？
やはり そうか。
I thought as much.
Then you must know already...
それなら もう
わかっているはずだな。
who is the reincarnate
of the younger one, Ashura...
弟 アシュラの転生者が誰なのかも。
(サスケ)ナルト…。
Naruto...
そうなんだろ？
Isn't that right?
そうだ やはり感じていたな。
Yes. You sensed it, after all.
俺や サスケの前にも→
It seems that there were
other reincarnates
その なんだ
転生者ってのがいたらしいけど→
besides Sasuke and me...
ソイツら 結局どうなったんだ？
Who were the others?
一世代前の転生者は
千手柱間と うちはマダラだった。
The first generation of reincarnates
were Hashirama Senju and Madara Uchiha.
柱間がアシュラ マダラがインドラだ。
Hashirama was Ashura.
Madara was Indra.
その２人が
どうなったかは わかるな？
You know how they ended up.
ただ マダラは 転生者を終える前に
ある問題を作ってしまった。
However, before Madara could end
his life as a reincarnate,
he created a certain problem.
力に とりつかれすぎたマダラは
柱間の力を奪った。
Madara was so obsessed with power
that he stole some of Hashirama's.
つまり それは
弟 アシュラの一部と→
Which, in short,
caused the merging
of a portion of Ashura's chakra
with Indra's chakra...
兄 インドラのチャクラを一つに
融合してしまうこととなり→
And the result was that
it became essentially, my own chakra.
わし自身のチャクラを
導き出してしまう結果となった。
そう 輪廻眼を開眼したのだ。
That's right,
he awakened the Rinnegan.
I always thought that someone
like that would appear
(ハゴロモ)インドラ…
そして インドラの転生側に→
そういう輩が
いずれは出現すると思っていた。
among either Indra
or his reincarnates.
だから わしは石碑を残し→
Hence, I left behind
the stone tablet
考えを改める導きを書き残した。
that contained my writings
on how to deal with this.
意味をなさなかったようだが。
Although, it seems no one could
understand its meaning...
So, Super Sage Gramps, you've been watching
じゃあ 仙人の大じいちゃんは→
ずっと自分の子供の
兄弟ゲンカを見てきたってことか。
your kids' sibling rivalry
all this time?
まあ そうなるな。
Yes, I suppose you could say that.
そうか…。
I see...
忍宗において チャクラは
個々を繋げる力と説いた。
Through Ninshu,
I preached that chakra is the power
that links individuals.
わしは チャクラを
個一つだけの力を→
I strongly believe that chakra
should not be something
that amplifies the strength
of one person alone.
増幅するものであっては
ならないと信じておる。
母であるカグヤは
乱世を終わらせた後も→
Even after my mother, Kaguya,
put an end to chaotic times,
一人だけで 世界を束ねた。
she ruled with her power alone.
が やがて 母の力は
うぬぼれを生み→
However, my mother's power
bred arrogance within her.
人々は その力の存在を
恐れるようになっていった。
And mankind began to dread
the existence of that power.
うさぎの女神と
呼ばれていた母が→
That is why my mother,
once known as the Rabbit Goddess,
いつしか鬼と恐れられるように
なったのも このためだ。
became feared as a demon.
力が一人に集中すれば
それは 暴走し→
When power is concentrated
in one person,
that power runs rampant and
in time, it possesses the person.
やがて 力に取りつかれてしまう。
今のマダラが まさにそれだ。
まるで 母 カグヤのようだ。
The current Madara is
a prime example of that...
He's become just like
my mother, Kaguya.
インドラの転生者を終えた今は
十尾の力を得て わしに近づき→
Now, he's no longer
Indra's incarnate.
He's obtained Ten Tails' power
and is getting close to me.
母 カグヤの力にさえ
近づこうとしている。
And he is trying to obtain even
my mother Kaguya's power.
無限月読とは
幻術にかけるだけではない。
The Infinite Tsukuyomi doesn't
just cast genjutsu over you.
幻術の夢を見せ続け 生かしたまま
個々の力を利用するために→
It keeps you trapped
inside genjutsu dreams,
so that the caster can use your
individual power while keeping you alive.
皆を神樹の根に繋げて
生きた奴隷とする幻術だ。
You're attached to the roots
of the Divine Tree,
and turned into living slaves.
母は 白眼以外に
写輪眼をも有していた。
Mother possessed the power
of Sharingan as well as Byakugan.
瞳力を使い その術を
民へと向けたこともある。
She used her Visual Prowess to cast
that jutsu upon the populace.
凄惨な術であった。
It was a ghastly jutsu.
チャクラが一つになってしまえば
また 新たなチャクラの実が出現する。
If all chakra were to
be reunited into one again,
a new Chakra Fruit
would take shape.
それだけは なんとしても
止めなければ 世界は終わる。
That must be prevented
at all costs...
or this world will end.
わしは お前に マダラを
止めてほしいと思っている。
I would like you to stop Madara.
今までの 転生者と違い
少々 バカっぽい。
Unlike the previous reincarnates,
you tend to be a little bit of a fool.
その意外性
そこに可能性があるかもしれん。
But there may be potential
in your unpredictability.
死んでさえ ずっと長えこと
見守ろうとしてきた世界が→
Even long after you died,
you tried to protect the world...
And even when
it's turned out like this,
こんなになってんのに
まだ俺たちのことを→
you still have faith in us.
Thank you.
信じてくれて ありがとう。
礼を言うな。
わしには そんな資格はない。
Don't thank me.
I don't deserve it.
今の世が インドラ…。
If the current world desires Indra's,
or rather, my mother's way...
いや 母のやり方を
本当は望んでいて→
それが自然の流れだとしたら→
and if that's the natural flow...
わしは 自分のわがままで
止めようとしていることになる。
then I'm the one who's selfishly
trying to go against it and stop it.
尾獣の使われ方にしてみても→
Even in terms of how
the Tailed Beasts are being used,
世の均衡と平和ではなく
兵器としてのみ使われる。
not for maintaining peace and balance,
but only as weapons...
わしの考えは甘いのかもしれんな。
Perhaps my way is naïve.
いや。
No!
大じいちゃんは 間違ってねえよ。
You're not wrong, Super Gramps!
そのとおりだぜ じじい！
You're absolutely right, old man!
あっ… 我愛羅んとこの…
なんで 俺の中に？
Oh, aren't you Gaara's?
Why are you inside of me?
オビトのヤツがな…。
You see, Obito...
八っつぁん!?
Octopops!
守鶴と俺のチャクラの一部を
マダラから引き抜いたんだ。
He extracted a portion of Shukaku's
and my chakra from Madara.
オメエに足りてねえ尾獣の力を→
He knew exactly which Tailed Beast
powers you were lacking, that guy!
ちゃんと
わかってやがったぜ アイツ。
オビトが…。
(九喇嘛)いろいろあってな。
Obito did that?
A lot of things happened.
わしも お前の中へ入れた。
He even put me inside of you.
(九喇嘛)これで
すべての尾獣のチャクラが→
Now you've got the chakra of all
nine Tailed Beasts within you, Naruto!
お前の中へ入ったぞ ナルト。
九喇嘛の もう片方のヤツまで…。
Even you?
The other half of Kurama?
これで やっと約束の時がきたぜ。
六道のじじいよ。
The promised time has
finally come, old man Six Paths!
そうだな 九喇嘛よ。
ガマ丸の予言どおり→
You're right, my dear Kurama...
Just as Gamamaru prophesied...
９匹の獣の名を呼び
戯れる碧眼の少年。
a blue-eyed youth who can name all
nine beasts and frolic among them.
予言って 大ガマ仙人が
エロ仙人に伝えた予言のこと？
Prophesied? You mean the prophecy
Giant Gramps Sage passed on
to the Pervy Sage?
ガマ丸ってのが本当の名前…。
Gamamaru is his real name?
そこまで知ってる
大じいちゃんてば→
You're pretty awesome because
you know that, Super Gramps!
やっぱ すげぇな！
Hey, Naruto!
おい ナルト。
えっ？
フフフフフ… お前は やはり
皆の協力を得る魅力があるようだ。
You truly have the ability
to win other's cooperation.
わしの魂を こうして呼べ
アシュラが転生したのも うなずける。
You managed to summon my soul.
And accepted that Ashura has
reincarnated inside of you.
ハハハ。
(ハゴロモ)守鶴 又旅。
Shukaku.
Matatabi.
磯撫 孫悟空 穆王。
Isobu.
Son Goku.
Kokuo.
犀犬 重明。
Saiken.
Chomei.
牛鬼 九喇嘛。
Gyuki.
Kurama.
予言の子が
世界を変えるときがきたようだ。
It seems the time has come...
for the child of prophecy
to change the world.
(ハゴロモ)ナルトよ。
My dear Naruto...
お前は何がしたい？
What do you want to do?
この戦いの果てに何を望む？
What do you seek for
the aftermath of this war?
お前の正直な考えを聞きたい。
I would like to hear
your honest thoughts and opinions.
確かに俺ってば
そのアシュラってヤツに似てっかもな。
Maybe I'm really like
this Ashura guy.
ただ ソイツと違ってバカでガキで→
Only... unlike him,
I'm just a stupid kid
いろんなこと よくわかんねえかも
しんねえけど→
who doesn't know much
about a lot of things.
仲間が
どういうもんかは知ってるよ。
But, I do know what friends are.
俺は それを守りてぇ。
そんだけだ。
And I want to protect them all.
That's it.
それが お前の答えか…。
Is that your answer?
ああ。
Yeah...
かつては
弟 アシュラにすべてを託し→
Long ago, I entrusted
everything to Ashura and
兄 インドラに目を向けてやることが
できなかった。
cast my attention away
from Indra.
それが災いのもととなった。
That proved to be
the source of calamity.
利き腕を出せ。
Put out your dominant arm.
此度は 兄 インドラの
転生者である お前にも→
This time, I am also entrusting
my power to you, Indra's reincarnate.
わしの力を託すことにした。
そして これから先 ナルトとサスケ→
From this point on,
Naruto and Sasuke...
お前たちが どうするか
どうなるかは お前たち次第だ。
What you both shall do,
and what shall transpire,
will be up to the two of you.
俺とナルトは…。
Naruto and I...
俺とサスケは
本当の兄弟じゃねえけど→
Sasuke and I...
... may not be real brothers,
仲直りは できると思うんだ。
but I really believe that
we can make peace.
俺たち かなりの友達だから。
Because we're pretty good friends.
さあ。
Now then...
(香燐)おい カブト！ サスケは？
サスケは 大丈夫なんだろうな!?
Hey, Kabuto!
Sasuke's... Sasuke's going
to be okay, right?
(香燐)おい！
なんとか言えよ！ この！
Hey, say something, you—!
あっ！
オビト！ ナルトは… ナルトは大丈夫なの？
Obito!
Is Naruto all right?
(オビト)人柱力のナルトは
尾獣を抜かれたら死ぬ。
Naruto the Jinchuriki will die if
his Tailed Beast is extracted...
だが 尾獣は入れた。
これで なんとかなるはずだ。
But I put the Tailed Beast
back inside him.
He should be okay now.
う…。
あっ！
サスケ！
Sasuke!
ナルト…。
Naruto!
(ナルト/サスケ)いくか。
– Time to go.
(マダラ)柱間以来だ このワクワクは。
You're the first since Hashirama
to make me feel this excited!
まだ踊れるだろ。
更に別の技はないのか？
Can you still dance?
Do you have any other techniques?
Give me some more fun!
もっと楽しませてくれ。
This guy... even after
a barrage of Sekizo...!
《ガイ : コイツ 連続の夕象を…》
Guy Sensei!
(リー)ガイ先生！
(我愛羅)あれでも ダメなのか…。
Even that... didn't work...
(カカシ)ハァ ハァ…。
ハァ ハァ…。
《夕象では ダメか…》
Sekizo... isn't enough!
ハハハッ いいぞ もっと踊れ。
This is great!
Keep on dancing!
《もう 夜ガイしかない…》
All that's left... is Night Guy!
Given the state of
his heart's Chakra Point,
心臓の点穴からみても
次が最後の攻撃となるな。
this will be his final attack...
積！
Charge!
あの構え 夕象じゃない！
That stance is not the Sekizo!
Don't tell me he has something
even greater!
まさか あれ以上の
技があるというのか…。
ガイ…。
Guy!
Come on, Dad, hurry!
((ほら 父さん急いで。
There's no need to rush.
(サクモ)慌てなくても
アカデミーは逃げやしないだろう？
The Academy isn't going
to run away, is it?
入学手続きの時間は
決まってるんだよ。
There's a set time for
entrance applications.
Oh, nice to meet you!
あっ はじめまして。
うちの子が これから
アカデミ-でお世話になります。
My son will be attending
the Academy.
父さん！
Dad...
I hope those two
will get along okay.
仲よくしてやってくださいね。
(ダイ)いや それは無理ですな。
I'm afraid that will
be impossible!
えっ えっ？ そんな…。
Huh? What a thing to say!
まさか モンスターペアレント？
Are you one of
those monster parents?!
いや 父さん違うんだよ。
No, Dad... You're wrong.
今回 コイツは
アカデミー試験に落ちたの。
He failed the Academy
entrance exam.
あっ… そ それは 失礼しました。
Oh, pardon me! I just assumed
since you were in front of the Academy.
アカデミーの前だったので つい…。
ハハハハハッ！
そういうわけなんですよ。
Don't worry about it!
そこ 笑うとこなの？
Uh, I don't think it's anything
to be laughing about.
こらっ カカシ！ 失礼だぞ。
Hey, Kakashi, don't be rude.
父さんのほうが もう
失礼かましちゃってるでしょ。
But Dad, you were a lot ruder
just a minute ago.
だいたいコイツは
忍者アカデミーに入ろうとしてんのに→
I mean, this guy is trying
to get in to the Academy
even though he can't
use ninjutsu.
忍術 使えないみたいだし
どう考えたって…。
っと… そろそろ行かないと
時間に遅れちゃうよ 父さん。
Oops, we should get going,
or we're going to be late.
Right.
あ ああ。
では…。
Excuse me.
はたけカカシだったな？
Your name's Kakashi Hatake, right?
ん？
応援ありがとう！
Thank you for your support!
は？
カカシ。
Kakashi...
Don't slack off just because
you got into the Academy.
アカデミー入学が決まったからって→
うかうかしてられないよ。
え？
このままいくと
あの子は お前より強くなる。
At the rate he's training,
that boy will become
stronger than you.
アイツが？
He will?
補欠の発表は まだだろう？
They haven't announced
the alternates yet, have they?
アカデミーもバカじゃない。
The Academy isn't dumb.
You should ask what his name is
and remember it.
彼の名前を聞いて
覚えておくといい。
え～！
What...?
He'll be a good rival for you.
いいライバルになるよ。
おい お前！
Hey, you!
名前は？
What's your name?
マイト・ガイ！
Might Guy!
(これから
誰よりも強くなる男だ！))
I'm going to become stronger
than anyone around!
((今回ばかりは
いいときに来てくれたよ。
You actually had perfect timing
for once...
(大丈夫か？ カカシ))
Are you all right, Kakashi?!
《本当に 父さんの
言ったとおりだったよ…。
Dad, it ended up exactly
as you predicted.
ガイ！》
Guy!
このチャクラ 認めてやろう。
I'll acknowledge
this chakra of yours!
体術において 俺の戦った者で→
Of all those who have
fought me over the years,
お前の右に出る者は
１人としておらん。
there's no one
who surpasses you at taijutsu!
このマダラが
お前を最強と呼んでやる！
I, Madara, declare you the strongest!
流！
Flow!
《速い！
He's fast!
なに 空間がねじ曲がっただと!?》
What?!
He's bending space?
夜ガイ！
Night Guy!
うわっ！
ガイ先生…。
Guy Sensei?
《これが ガイの最後の技。
That was Guy's final move!
どうなった？》
What happened?
ハァ ハァ…。
ハハハッ
死ぬところだったぜ こやつめ。
I almost died, you bastard!
風前の灯火だが
楽しませてくれた 礼だ。
Your flame is about to go out...
But in gratitude for
such a great time,
灰になる前に→
I'll finish you off...
俺が殺してやる！
before you turn to ash
on your own!
《求道玉を蹴るだと!?》
He kicked away my Truthseeker Orb?!
ゲキマユ先生…。
Bushier Brow Sensei...
(マダラ)ナルト…。
Naruto...?
いや なんとなく前とは違うな。
You seem a little different
from before.
《オビトのヤツが…》
What did Obito do?
あぁ。
Yeah...
自分でも不思議に思うってばよ。
I'm still trying to figure it out myself.
今なら全部を変えられそうだ！
But I think I can change
everything now!
terase asu wo ima kokoro tsutau messeeji
Shine a light, tomorrow is now,
a message straight to the heart
boku to yoku ni ta itami uchiake te kure ta hito
Hearing someone tell me about
the same kind of pain I have
futo hitori ja nain datte omoetan da
Made me think that I'm not alone
dakedo nagareta namida kamishime ta nukumori o
But the flowing tears and the warmth I relished
itsumade mo boku wa dakishimete ireru ka na?
How long can those envelop me?
kizutsui te kizutsui te nai te nai te tsuyoku nare subete
Hurting again and again,
crying over and over gives you strength for everything
me ni utsuru sono keshiki wa eien ni tada kokoro e to
That scenery you see goes straight to the heart,
massugu tsunagatte iku
now and forever
hanate niji no sora omoi nara koko ni aru (my heart)
Let it go, the rainbow sky, my wishes are here (My heart)
terase asu wo ima kokoro tsutau messeeji
Shine a light, tomorrow is now,
a message straight to the heart
hanate niji no sora
Let it go, the rainbow sky
I know I just came back,
but the next episode's an extra!
It's been three years since
I was back in the village,
オープニングは にぎやかに→
and Konohamaru's pestering me
to teach him a new jutsu!
夏のお祭り気分とまいりましょう。
『大東京音頭』。
I guess I have no choice!
皆さん お手拍子 お願いします。
Well, I'll just have to teach him
one amazing jutsu!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Ones Who Will Inherit"
Konohamaru, just GAAH it
and BAM it!